ICICI Lombard and CNBC tv18 percent in
their risk management Awards my first
question I didn't this is because you
also raised that issue are we a bit of
children or the 2008 crisis that will be
call everything or crisis I mean maybe
more scared of financial events than
libel in the past is there is there that
likelihood I I really don't think that
we always can talk about crises in the
well what would called systemic which is
what we saw in 2008-2009 and then
there's always milder let me say that in
terms of how would I characterize some
of the problems I described for India in
in in banking some of those had the
element of boom box this was around you
know the the the 2000 2008 and some of
them are what I would call slower burn
they're more structural and this has to
do with the credit allocation in the
publicly owned back so they don't have
that crisis crisis that things are gonna
you know and to some important degree
the same distinction is applicable when
we talk about climate change climate
change this I mean it can be very
drastic it's the the real threat in the
real threat in economies that are facing
like Australia large-scale fire or a
tropical storm that's better but that's
something but many of those were
our slower burn but there's the risk and
that's what I tried to highlight in some
of my presentation the other issue that
comes to the mind is that in spite of
this exponential increase in government
debt and the fact that corporates are
more indebted than ever before or
certainly more than they were in between
2008 contraction and nordley as you
pointed out that interest rates are
already negative and so even the
monetary space is next to nothing
in spite of all this we see double
market equity markets reaching out to
all-time high and this is especially the
case the United States which also have
much less more free space and
practically even less disgusting yeah
are we is this indicating something
different that something right is
happening or is it indicating that this
is a blind spot and we better be worried
about the way equity markets are
charging there are things that are
different there always are we in our
work can Rogoff an eye that this time is
different it's meant to be ironic but
that's really about human nature which
seldom is different but let me get to
your question on equity markets um part
of the equity market story is definitely
tied to the exceptionally low for long
interest rate there is a search field
the search for yield is not just these
asset managers that managing pension
funds asset managers that were once
predominantly in fixed income and have
had to seek higher returns in the equity
market it is sovereign wealth funds that
historically like central banks who are
predominantly fixed income and have to
so there are structural elements to the
shift to the extent that some of the
reasons some of the reasons that
interest rates are low have to do with
aging population some of them have to do
with lower productivity so some of these
trends to lower interest rate are
secular however one has to be prepared
that to the extent that some of the
interest rate decline is not permanent
that there could be adverse shocks
inflation surprises and the like that
would lead even without melodrama to
some increase in interest rates then I
think those equity markets will be
sorely tested because right now I think
there's a great deal of complacency that
it's not that rates are low for long is
that inflation in bed and rates are low
forever which is saying forever in
economics is always dangerous that's
sort of a rule of thumb okay may I
invite mr. Braga the star to join us
[Applause]
by the veteran of managing risk so I
thought I should heard a few questions
that you is very you've been discussing
a lot of financial issues and how those
risks can be managed and mitigated but
you know what you must now be
encountering are you know existential
risks but enemies you previously
disrupted by digital so many people not
watching our program except as what's
your own livestock markets the rest of
it is available digitally only toxins
watched because it's a live event so
similar disruptions we have seen for the
automobile sector with Millennials not
wanting to own the car how do you manage
these kinds of things so linked that's
something that we insurance marriage
that marriage it's I think each company
has to think about how do they manage
their existence and you know you know
ultimately we are all serving customers
customers are human beings who have
needs which transcend time right they
oppose these change and morph in some
way or form but the foundation of those
needs are probably similar what you're
talking about is you'll see in the case
of a car is a transportation need you
want to move from one place to another
in the case of television it's more
maybe information or entertainment the
way you provide that solution to your
customer can change and that's what
maybe technology does I think the other
aspect of technology is that you know it
creates disruption but it also creates
opportunity you know for example when we
look at risk for our own businesses we
talked about catastrophic risks and we
talked about event rates etcetera and
let's say in the past
traditionally lorem been waiting for it
to happen and then we come in and you
know let's say you know pay a claim
today you can actually monitor and hence
prevent some of these events using
sensors and and you know for example in
the automobile example that you're
talking about one of the biggest worries
that we have as insurers is that if
everyone moves into autonomous vehicles
sale driven cars the rate of accidents
drop by 80% what happens to our business
you're all set up - right exactly
if I if I can take give the last
question from you either you talked
about the fact that
the last question that he replied was
real US dollar event there is no correct
color similar me you know we were
talking there that this is prolly or the
most interesting question to ask
so let me ask you that question to you
do not worry about how happy I am so
happy you've done that look I just
finished a study with ten Ken Rogoff who
was here last year and Ethan else asked
a former student of mine looking at this
very issue if anything the dollar has
gained ground in the last two years
because the euro has lost ground in the
euro has lost ground because yes there
is one year or one Percy but there isn't
a unified debt market you have a very
fragmented your boobs you have Greek
debt it's not a it's a fragmented market
so what worries me is what the Euro the
so-called ultra-thin dilemma in which to
service as a reserve currency you wish
you more debt because the world wants to
hold more debt but at the same time you
saw the debt numbers for the US so at
one at one point in time the to class
you know those there those way you ask
yes the rest of the world wants more
debt will issue more debt and up what at
one point does that lead to a dollar
depreciation at the moment there's no
alternative to the dollar left with love
big alternative but that may change over
time well it's an interesting
organization thank you very much to
combine all the pleasure speaking with
you now cook the eyes very thank you
very much for joining us in the shuttle
ICICI Lombard and CNBC tv18 presents
India risk management Awards